<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mahdi Sadjadi</title>
    <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mahdi Sadjadi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mahdi Sadjadi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ArxivScraper: A python module based on arxiv.org API</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/arxiv_scraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/arxiv_scraper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arxiv.org is a repository for scientific preprints in various fields of
study. Visiting the website daily to find the latest papers is a routine for
many researchers. However, Arxiv receives thousands of monthly submissions and
researchers often have to browse tens of papers to find preprints relevant to
their research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arxivscraper is a python module written to simplify the access to
related papers in a given area. The user can pass a category and a date range
to receive all papers submitted or update within that range. The user has also
the option to filter those papers based on their author, subcategory, title and
abstract. For more information on how to install and use the module, see its
GitHub repository:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/arxivscraper&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/arxivscraper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix crime analysis</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/phoenix_crimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/phoenix_crimes/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/phoenixcrime/raw/master/heatmap.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;weekly crime trend&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Analysis of crime data is not only important to prevent criminal acts and to
provide a safer environment, it contains rich interesting patterns related to
the local community, geography and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city of Phoenix has published such data since November 2015. In this project,
I look at the crimes trend in Phoenix, AZ. The weekly and monthly trends
of various crime types are studied. I also provide a D3 visualization of
weekly trends for all crime types. In addition, safer zip codes are determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Bernoulli Naive Bayes classifier is trained on data to predict the type of
a crime given its location and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/phoenixcrime&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/phoenixcrime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Webpage: &lt;a href=&#34;http://mahdisadjadi.com/phoenixcrime/&#34;&gt;http://mahdisadjadi.com/phoenixcrime/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipeline incidents in the US</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/oil_pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/oil_pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/img/20161203_pipeline_output_29_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/pipeline-incidents&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/pipeline-incidents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Report (blog post): &lt;a href=&#34;http://mahdisadjadi.com/blog/20161203_pipeline/&#34;&gt;http://mahdisadjadi.com/blog/20161203_pipeline/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular materials</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/cellular_materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/cellular_materials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can barely find someone not amazed by honeycombs: a packing of seemingly
perfect hexagons. Honeycomb is a cellular network. In fact,
they are many similar structures in nature resembling the honeycomb. Although,
most naturally occurring cellular networks are not as ordered as honeycomb. But
it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to notice in the image (top left corner), even in honeycomb
there are a few cells with 5 neighbors instead of 6.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newdesignfile.com/post_honeycomb-texture-psd-free_202486/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/img/projects_cellmaterials_01.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Honeycomb, a cellular material&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Partitioning any surface or volume into closed
cells results in a &amp;ldquo;cellular network&amp;rdquo;.
Examples are soap foam, grains, biological tissues, crack networks, ecological
territories, and Voronoi tessellations. It is amazing how very distinct processes
lead to cellular networks which are topologically the same. The following image
shows bubbles as a cellular network where an interface separates order-disorder phases.
If you look at the disordered phase carefully, you will notice that large bubbles are
surrounded by small bubbles. This is no accident! This
tendency of smaller and larger rings being adjacent is called &amp;ldquo;Aboav-Weaire&amp;rdquo; law.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Order_and_Chaos.tif&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/img/projects_cellmaterials_02.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;A foam with interface order-disorder&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;According to the law, average size of cells $m(n)$ around a cell with $n$ sides is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
m(n) = A+\frac{B}{n}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$A$ and $B$ are two constants determined for each specific network. This is not
an exact equation but works very well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interest in cellular networks comes from network glasses. Although in glass science,
they are often called random network instead of cellular network and cells
are called &amp;ldquo;rings&amp;rdquo;. Network glasses are very important networks since they
are microscopic and interactions are vert different from commonly studied random
networks. But the issue is, rings in bulk glasses (which are 3D) are hard to
observe or even define uniquely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breakthrough happened only recently. Researchers have been able to image
a bilayer silica (SiO${}_{2}$) showing, for the very first time, how atoms are arranged to
make the network of polygons creating the ring structure of the glass.
Another example of these thin materials is
amorphous graphene. Although people have studied glasses for years, the issue is
 their structure is disordered (and there are $~10^{23}$ atoms to image!),
so experimental methods used in crystallography (like x-ray) can&amp;rsquo;t determine
the structure uniquely. This leaves a lot of room for &lt;em&gt;scientific&lt;/em&gt; speculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note how different these materials are, ranging from atomic scale to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although my research is mainly concerned with fundamental aspects of cellular
materials but they also have wide applications. These materials are low density
(lightweight) and are suitable to make boats, airplane and our bones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] Sadjadi M, Thorpe MF. Ring correlations in random networks. Physical Review E. 2016 Dec 9;94(6):062304.
arXiv:&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1607.06568&#34;&gt;1607.06568&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062304&#34;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt; (2016).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
