<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mahdi Sadjadi</title>
    <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mahdi Sadjadi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Mahdi Sadjadi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArxivScraper: A python module based on arxiv.org API</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/arxiv_scraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/arxiv_scraper/</guid>
      <description>Arxiv.org is a repository for scientific preprints in various fields of study. Visiting the website daily to find the latest papers is a routine for many researchers. However, Arxiv receives thousands of monthly submissions and researchers often have to browse tens of papers to find preprints relevant to their research.
Arxivscraper is a python module written to simplify the access to related papers in a given area. The user can pass a category and a date range to receive all papers submitted or updated during that range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix crime analysis</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/phoenix_crimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/phoenix_crimes/</guid>
      <description>weekly crime trend   Analysis of crime data is not only important to prevent criminal acts and to provide a safer environment, it contains rich interesting patterns related to the local community, geography and culture.
The city of Phoenix has published such data since November 2015. In this project, I look at the crimes trend in Phoenix, AZ. The weekly and monthly trends of various crime types are studied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipeline incidents in the US</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/oil_pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/oil_pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Repository: https://github.com/Mahdisadjadi/pipeline-incidents
Report (blog post): http://mahdisadjadi.com/blog/20161203_pipeline/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular materials</title>
      <link>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/cellular_materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mahdisadjadi.github.io/project/cellular_materials/</guid>
      <description>You can barely find someone not amazed by honeycombs: a packing of seemingly perfect hexagons. Honeycomb is a cellular network. In fact, they are many similar structures in nature resembling the honeycomb. Although, most naturally occurring cellular networks are not as ordered as honeycomb. But it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to notice in the image (top left corner), even in honeycomb there are a few cells with 5 neighbors instead of 6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>